<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<Defs>
	<BackstoryDef Name="CFAR_Adult" Abstract="True">
		<requiresSpawnCategory>true</requiresSpawnCategory>
		<slot>Adulthood</slot>
		<bodyTypeMale>Male</bodyTypeMale>
		<bodyTypeFemale>Female</bodyTypeFemale>
	</BackstoryDef>
	
<!--================ White Collar ================-->

<!--======== Business ========-->

	<BackstoryDef Name="CFAR_OfficeWorker" ParentName="CFAR_Adult">
		<defName>CFAR_OfficeWorker1</defName>
		<title>Office worker</title>
		<titleShort>Office worker</titleShort>
		<description>WIP</description>
		<skillGains>
			<Social>5</Social>
			<Intellectual>3</Intellectual>
		</skillGains>
		<spawnCategories>
			<li>CFAR_OfficeWorker</li>
		</spawnCategories>
	</BackstoryDef>

	<BackstoryDef ParentName="CFAR_OfficeWorker">
		<defName>CFAR_OfficeWorker2</defName>
		<description>WIP</description>
	</BackstoryDef>
	
<!--================ Imperial Naval Infantry Command ================-->

<!--======== Trooper ========-->

	<BackstoryDef Name="CFAR_Trooper" ParentName="CFAR_Adult">
		<defName>CFAR_Trooper1</defName>
		<title>imperial trooper</title>
		<titleShort>trooper</titleShort>
		<description>[PAWN_nameDef] was a trooper in the Imperial Navy. [PAWN_pronoun] thought war would be dramatic; it was mostly checking corridors and fixing jammed hatches. Still, [PAWN_nameDef] kept [PAWN_possessive] gear sharp and helmet visor polished.</description>
		<skillGains>
			<Shooting>6</Shooting>
			<Melee>2</Melee>
		</skillGains>
		<spawnCategories>
			<li>CFAR_Trooper</li>
		</spawnCategories>
	</BackstoryDef>

	<BackstoryDef ParentName="CFAR_Trooper">
		<defName>CFAR_Trooper2</defName>
		<description>[PAWN_nameDef] was a trooper in the imperial navy. [PAWN_pronoun] handled weapons locker checks and ran escort drills weekly. [PAWN_pronoun] cleaned rifles more than [PAWN_pronoun] fired them. Still, when orders came, [PAWN_nameDef] was always ready.</description>
	</BackstoryDef>

	<BackstoryDef ParentName="CFAR_Trooper">
		<defName>CFAR_Trooper3</defName>
		<description>[PAWN_nameDef] was a trooper in the Imperial Navy. [PAWN_pronoun] passed time guarding hangars and rerouting power lines. [PAWN_pronoun] memorized patrol routes and brewed coffee in engine heat.</description>
	</BackstoryDef>

	<BackstoryDef ParentName="CFAR_Trooper">
		<defName>CFAR_Trooper4</defName>
		<description>[PAWN_nameDef] was a trooper in the Imperial Navy. [PAWN_pronoun] spent long hours guarding fuel lines and sweeping docking bays. [PAWN_pronoun] knew the hum of every generator by heart. Off-shift, [PAWN_pronoun] traded bad jokes and played cards with the squad, always folding too early.</description>
	</BackstoryDef>

	<BackstoryDef ParentName="CFAR_Trooper">
		<defName>CFAR_Trooper5</defName>
		<description>[PAWN_nameDef] was a trooper in the Imperial Navy. Whenever [PAWN_possessive] unit raided a pirate outpost, [PAWN_pronoun] set the trigger to full-auto, blasting pirates until they stood no more.</description>
	</BackstoryDef>

	<BackstoryDef ParentName="CFAR_Trooper">
		<defName>CFAR_Trooper6</defName>
		<description>[PAWN_nameDef] was a trooper in the Imperial Navy. [PAWN_pronoun] cleared hallways in pirate outposts with short bursts and steady steps. No heroics—just corners, cover, and commands. After the sweep, [PAWN_pronoun] helped tag crates and carry bodies.</description>
	</BackstoryDef>

	<BackstoryDef ParentName="CFAR_Trooper">
		<defName>CFAR_Trooper7</defName>
		<description>[PAWN_nameDef] was a trooper in the Imperial Navy. [PAWN_pronoun] followed orders, covered sectors, and kept the pulse rifle warm. Pirate outposts all smelled the same—burnt plastic and fear. [PAWN_pronoun] didn’t mind the work. It was simple.</description>
	</BackstoryDef>

	<BackstoryDef ParentName="CFAR_Trooper">
		<defName>CFAR_Trooper8</defName>
		<description>[PAWN_nameDef] was a trooper in the Imperial Navy. During pirate raids, [PAWN_pronoun] lobbed thermal detonators into rooms before stepping in. It wasn’t subtle, but it worked. [PAWN_pronoun] carried extra, clipped across [PAWN_possessive] belt, and used them often. No one complained.</description>
	</BackstoryDef>

	<BackstoryDef ParentName="CFAR_Trooper">
		<defName>CFAR_Trooper9</defName>
		<description>[PAWN_nameDef] was a trooper in the Imperial Navy. Fighting deserters felt wrong—they wore old uniforms, spoke the same codes. [PAWN_pronoun] still aimed center mass. Patrols turned tense; friendlies weren’t always friendly. [PAWN_pronoun] learned quick: hesitate, and you die.</description>
	</BackstoryDef>

	<BackstoryDef ParentName="CFAR_Trooper">
		<defName>CFAR_Trooper10</defName>
		<description>[PAWN_nameDef] was a trooper in the Imperial Navy. Deserters used old callsigns and spoke like comrades. It made [PAWN_pronoun] pause, unsure if the welcome was real. [PAWN_pronoun] kept a finger near the trigger, but waited. Something always felt off.</description>
	</BackstoryDef>

	<BackstoryDef ParentName="CFAR_Trooper">
		<defName>CFAR_Trooper11</defName>
		<description>[PAWN_nameDef] was a trooper in the Imperial Navy. Desertion meant betrayal, but it didn’t feel that simple. [PAWN_pronoun] swept camps where deserters shared old jokes and cooked Navy meals. [PAWN_pronoun] fired anyway. Good soldiers followed orders.</description>
	</BackstoryDef>

	<BackstoryDef ParentName="CFAR_Trooper">
		<defName>CFAR_Trooper12</defName>
		<description>[PAWN_nameDef] was a trooper in the Imperial Navy. The deserters fought like trained squads—disciplined, tight formations. [PAWN_pronoun] won the fight, but it didn’t feel like victory. It felt like shooting [PAWN_possessive] comrades—which they were, at one point.</description>
	</BackstoryDef>

	<BackstoryDef ParentName="CFAR_Trooper" MayRequire="Ludeon.RimWorld.Anomaly">
		<defName>CFAR_Trooper13</defName>
		<description>[PAWN_nameDef] was a trooper in the Imperial Navy. The infected looked human—until they moved. Too fast, too stiff. [PAWN_pronoun] learned to spot the signs: flickering eyes, metal under skin. [PAWN_pronoun] kept the helmet sealed and the safety off.</description>
	</BackstoryDef>

	<BackstoryDef ParentName="CFAR_Trooper" MayRequire="Ludeon.RimWorld.Anomaly">
		<defName>CFAR_Trooper14</defName>
		<description>[PAWN_nameDef] was a trooper in the Imperial Navy. The shamblers moved wrong—silent, twitching, eyes like old comrades. Pulse fire barely slowed them. After the first sweep, [PAWN_pronoun] stopped talking. The squad left the lights on, even when they slept.</description>
	</BackstoryDef>

<!--======== Heavy Trooper ========-->

	<BackstoryDef Name="CFAR_HeavyTrooper" ParentName="CFAR_Adult">
		<defName>CFAR_HeavyTrooper1</defName>
		<title>heavy trooper</title>
		<titleShort>trooper</titleShort>
		<description>[PAWN_nameDef] was a heavy trooper in the Imperial Navy. [PAWN_pronoun] carried the pulse repeater like a second arm—slow, steady, deadly. When the line broke, [PAWN_pronoun] held it together with bursts of suppressing fire.</description>
		<skillGains>
			<Shooting>6</Shooting>
			<Melee>4</Melee>
		</skillGains>
		<spawnCategories>
			<li>CFAR_HeavyTrooper</li>
		</spawnCategories>
	</BackstoryDef>

	<BackstoryDef ParentName="CFAR_HeavyTrooper">
		<defName>CFAR_HeavyTrooper2</defName>
		<description>[PAWN_nameDef] was a heavy trooper in the Imperial Navy. Hordes of enemies poured in, but [PAWN_pronoun] just kept mowing them down, like clockwork. [PAWN_pronoun] wasn’t even sweating anymore. It was boring, really—just another day of endless fire and too much blood to wipe off [PAWN_possessive] gear.</description>
	</BackstoryDef>

	<BackstoryDef ParentName="CFAR_HeavyTrooper">
		<defName>CFAR_HeavyTrooper3</defName>
		<description>[PAWN_nameDef] was a heavy trooper in the Imperial Navy. [PAWN_pronoun] wasn’t just fighting—[PAWN_pronoun] was having a blast. The pulse cannon kicked like a beast, and the explosions were music to [PAWN_pronoun]’s ears. [PAWN_pronoun] didn’t care about the chaos. This was the job.</description>
	</BackstoryDef>

	<BackstoryDef ParentName="CFAR_HeavyTrooper">
		<defName>CFAR_HeavyTrooper4</defName>
		<description>[PAWN_nameDef] was a heavy trooper in the Imperial Navy. The pulse repeater was a part of [PAWN_pronoun] like a second arm. When [PAWN_pronoun] opened fire, the battlefield turned into a spectacle—bright, loud, and impossible to ignore. And [PAWN_pronoun] wouldn’t have it any other way.</description>
	</BackstoryDef>

	<BackstoryDef ParentName="CFAR_HeavyTrooper">
		<defName>CFAR_HeavyTrooper5</defName>
		<description>[PAWN_nameDef] was a heavy trooper in the Imperial Navy. Munching on a sandwich while covering fire was [PAWN_possessive] specialty. The battlefield was chaotic, but hunger was constant—and louder than the pulse cannon.</description>
	</BackstoryDef>

	<BackstoryDef ParentName="CFAR_HeavyTrooper">
		<defName>CFAR_HeavyTrooper6</defName>
		<description>[PAWN_nameDef] was a heavy trooper in the Imperial Navy. Slow to anger, quick with a joke, [PAWN_pronoun] carried the pulse repeater like it was an old friend. Between firefights, [PAWN_pronoun] lounged with the squad, keeping the mood light.</description>
	</BackstoryDef>

<!--======== Recon Trooper ========-->

	<BackstoryDef Name="CFAR_ReconTrooper" ParentName="CFAR_Adult">
		<defName>CFAR_ReconTrooper1</defName>
		<title>recon trooper</title>
		<titleShort>trooper</titleShort>
		<description>[PAWN_nameDef] was a recon trooper in the Imperial Navy. [PAWN_pronoun] preferred the quiet, the solitude. With a cloaking module and pulse railgun, [PAWN_pronoun] was a shadow in the dark, watching, waiting. [PAWN_pronoun] never missed—[PAWN_possessive] silence was as much a weapon as the gun.</description>
		<skillGains>
			<Shooting>8</Shooting>
			<Melee>2</Melee>
			<Social>-2</Social>
		</skillGains>
		<spawnCategories>
			<li>CFAR_ReconTrooper</li>
		</spawnCategories>
	</BackstoryDef>

	<BackstoryDef ParentName="CFAR_ReconTrooper">
		<defName>CFAR_ReconTrooper2</defName>
		<description>[PAWN_nameDef] was a recon trooper in the Imperial Navy. Silent and unnoticed, [PAWN_pronoun] moved through shadows, pulse railgun always at the ready. [PAWN_pronoun] didn’t need to speak—one clean shot was all that mattered. The world didn’t know [PAWN_pronoun] was there until it was too late.</description>
	</BackstoryDef>

	<BackstoryDef ParentName="CFAR_ReconTrooper">
		<defName>CFAR_ReconTrooper3</defName>
		<description>[PAWN_nameDef] was a recon trooper in the Imperial Navy. [PAWN_pronoun] was all about stealth... except when [PAWN_pronoun] tripped over a crate during a recon mission. [PAWN_pronoun] didn’t make a sound after that—mostly because [PAWN_pronoun] was hiding in a corner, pretending to be a rock.</description>
	</BackstoryDef>

	<BackstoryDef ParentName="CFAR_ReconTrooper">
		<defName>CFAR_ReconTrooper4</defName>
		<description>[PAWN_nameDef] was a recon trooper in the Imperial Navy. With the cloaking module on and pulse railgun ready, [PAWN_pronoun] would vanish into the environment. [PAWN_pronoun] was good at "surveying" the battlefield... and occasionally skipping patrols to sneak in a nap. No one ever saw [PAWN_pronoun] anyway.</description>
	</BackstoryDef>

	<BackstoryDef ParentName="CFAR_ReconTrooper">
		<defName>CFAR_ReconTrooper5</defName>
		<description>[PAWN_nameDef] was a recon trooper in the Imperial Navy. [PAWN_pronoun] could vanish at will, using the cloaking module to stay hidden for hours. Sometimes, it was easier to just avoid the fight entirely—stay in position, watch, and let others do the hard work. The mission could wait.</description>
	</BackstoryDef>

	<BackstoryDef ParentName="CFAR_ReconTrooper">
		<defName>CFAR_ReconTrooper6</defName>
		<description>[PAWN_nameDef] was a recon trooper in the Imperial Navy. Armed with a pulse railgun and cloaking tech, [PAWN_pronoun] preferred to let others deal with the mess. [PAWN_pronoun] took a lot of "recon" breaks, finding remote spots to watch the chaos unfold, out of sight, away from responsibility.</description>
	</BackstoryDef>

<!--======== Jet Trooper ========-->

	<BackstoryDef Name="CFAR_JetTrooper" ParentName="CFAR_Adult">
		<defName>CFAR_JetTrooper1</defName>
		<title>jet trooper</title>
		<titleShort>trooper</titleShort>
		<description>[PAWN_nameDef] was a jet trooper in the Imperial Navy. Most soldiers stayed on the ground, but [PAWN_pronoun] never did. Jumping was a dance, dodging fire and sending enemies scrambling in all directions. Sure, it made [PAWN_pronoun] a big target—but what’s life without a little risk?</description>
		<skillGains>
			<Shooting>6</Shooting>
			<Melee>2</Melee>
		</skillGains>
		<spawnCategories>
			<li>CFAR_ReconTrooper</li>
		</spawnCategories>
	</BackstoryDef>

	<BackstoryDef ParentName="CFAR_JetTrooper">
		<defName>CFAR_JetTrooper2</defName>
		<description>[PAWN_nameDef] was a jet trooper in the Imperial Navy. When not in the air, [PAWN_pronoun] could be found checking equipment, adjusting thrusters, or doing a hundred laps around the hangar. There was always something to improve, always something to break—[PAWN_pronoun] liked it that way.</description>
	</BackstoryDef>

	<BackstoryDef ParentName="CFAR_JetTrooper">
		<defName>CFAR_JetTrooper3</defName>
		<description>[PAWN_nameDef] was a jet trooper in the Imperial Navy. Between maintenance checks and test jumps, [PAWN_pronoun] could always be found at the table, rolling dice or flipping cards. The adrenaline rush of the jump wasn’t enough—[PAWN_pronoun] needed the thrill of the gamble to keep the edge sharp.</description>
	</BackstoryDef>

	<BackstoryDef ParentName="CFAR_JetTrooper">
		<defName>CFAR_JetTrooper4</defName>
		<description>[PAWN_nameDef] was a jet trooper in the Imperial Navy. [PAWN_pronoun] jumped high, fired fast, and bet hard. After a successful run, [PAWN_pronoun] would kick back with a few hands of poker, trying to win it all back—or lose it all and jump again for the next thrill.</description>
	</BackstoryDef>

	<BackstoryDef ParentName="CFAR_JetTrooper">
		<defName>CFAR_JetTrooper5</defName>
		<description>[PAWN_nameDef] was a jet trooper in the Imperial Navy. Snacks vanished from the mess hall like clockwork—usually just before [PAWN_pronoun] took off on a mission. The stolen chocolates kept [PAWN_pronoun] fueled for the next jump.</description>
	</BackstoryDef>

	<BackstoryDef ParentName="CFAR_JetTrooper">
		<defName>CFAR_JetTrooper6</defName>
		<description>[PAWN_nameDef] was a jet trooper in the Imperial Navy. [PAWN_pronoun] had a knack for swiping sweets unnoticed, hiding chocolate bars in [PAWN_possessive] armor. The thrill wasn’t just in the air—it was in the small victories on the ground.</description>
	</BackstoryDef>

<!--======== Lieutenant ========-->

	<BackstoryDef Name="CFAR_Lieutenant" ParentName="CFAR_Adult">
		<defName>CFAR_Lieutenant1</defName>
		<title>lieutenant</title>
		<titleShort>lieutenant</titleShort>
		<description>[PAWN_nameDef] was a lieutenant in the Imperial Navy. Orders were clear, but troopers always added their own spin. It drove [PAWN_pronoun] nuts, but deep down, [PAWN_pronoun] knew [PAWN_possessive] squad was loyal through and through.</description>
		<skillGains>
			<Shooting>4</Shooting>
			<Melee>-2</Melee>
			<Social>6</Social>
		</skillGains>
		<spawnCategories>
			<li>CFAR_Lieutenant</li>
		</spawnCategories>
	</BackstoryDef>

	<BackstoryDef ParentName="CFAR_Lieutenant">
		<defName>CFAR_Lieutenant2</defName>
		<description>[PAWN_nameDef] was a lieutenant in the Imperial Navy. [PAWN_pronoun] knew the troopers tested limits and took chances, but sergeants kept them grounded. Where [PAWN_pronoun] issued orders and made plans, sergeants enforced discipline and settled disputes. The two ranks worked side by side, one controlling chaos through command, the other through force.</description>
	</BackstoryDef>

	<BackstoryDef ParentName="CFAR_Lieutenant">
		<defName>CFAR_Lieutenant3</defName>
		<description>[PAWN_nameDef] was a lieutenant in the Imperial Navy. Promotions weren’t just about skill; they were about who you knew and how you played the game. [PAWN_pronoun] watched colleagues like a hawk, tracking alliances and rivalries that could make or break a career. The war was one battle—the officer’s mess was another, equally brutal.</description>
	</BackstoryDef>

	<BackstoryDef ParentName="CFAR_Lieutenant">
		<defName>CFAR_Lieutenant4</defName>
		<description>[PAWN_nameDef] was a lieutenant in the Imperial Navy. Strategy meetings were thinly veiled political battlegrounds. [PAWN_pronoun] learned to choose words with care, weigh every statement, and pick fights wisely. Sometimes walking away was smarter than fighting—and survival meant knowing which was which.</description>
	</BackstoryDef>

	<BackstoryDef ParentName="CFAR_Lieutenant">
		<defName>CFAR_Lieutenant5</defName>
		<description>[PAWN_nameDef] was a lieutenant in the Imperial Navy. When the order came to engage deserters, [PAWN_pronoun] hesitated. They wore the same uniform once, carried the same hopes. Each shot from [PAWN_possessive] pulse pistol weighed heavy—a reminder that this was more than just a fight; it was kin against kin.</description>
	</BackstoryDef>

	<BackstoryDef ParentName="CFAR_Lieutenant">
		<defName>CFAR_Lieutenant6</defName>
		<description>[PAWN_nameDef] was a trooper in the Imperial Navy. When the deserters showed their faces, [PAWN_pronoun] gripped [PAWN_possessive] pulse pistol tighter than ever. Fury burned in [PAWN_possessive] veins—not just at the enemy, but at the betrayal they represented. Every shot was a statement: loyalty over all.</description>
	</BackstoryDef>

	<BackstoryDef ParentName="CFAR_Lieutenant" MayRequire="Ludeon.RimWorld.Anomaly">
		<defName>CFAR_Lieutenant7</defName>
		<description>[PAWN_nameDef] was a lieutenant in the Imperial Navy. The infestation didn’t just consume bodies—it ate trust. [PAWN_pronoun] watched [PAWN_possessive] own squad with suspicion, every twitch and glance a potential threat. Orders turned into tests, and camaraderie became a fragile illusion.</description>
	</BackstoryDef>

	<BackstoryDef ParentName="CFAR_Lieutenant" MayRequire="Ludeon.RimWorld.Anomaly">
		<defName>CFAR_Lieutenant8</defName>
		<description>[PAWN_nameDef] was a lieutenant in the Imperial Navy. As metalhorror spread, trust frayed and suspicion grew. [PAWN_pronoun] isolated troopers, interrogated friends, and watched shadows. The war was no longer just external—it was inside the squad.</description>
	</BackstoryDef>
</Defs>
